This time, I'm not giving up, no matter what!
這次我絕對不會放棄！
EPISODE 4: FORTITUDE 9.8
（第4集：怪獸規模9.8）
Senpai, are you okay?
前輩，你沒事吧？
See? I can still stand!
你看，我還站得起來
He just stood up on his broken leg, right?
他用骨折的那隻腳站起來了
Well, if that's your choice.
真是沒辦法
If I think it looks bad, I'm turning the remote shield on, okay?
要是情況不妙 我會馬上啟動遠端防護盾喔
Fine by me!
正合我意
Ichikawa, don't worry about me. Go on.
市川，你不用在意我，儘管衝吧
We had a deal, right?
我們說好了
If something happens to me, you can...
就算我出了什麼事，你也不用…
I'll back you up.
我會支援你的
Let's do the best we can.
我們一起卯足全力應戰吧
Ichikawa...
市川…
That's just who you are, isn't it?
你就是這種人啊，不是嗎？
All right, if you insist!
既然你都這麼說了
Are these guys for real?
這兩個人是認真的嗎？
Let's go, Ichikawa!
市川，我們上！
By our powers combined!
採取合體作戰！
Everyone's staring at me, and I'm really embarrassed!
大家都在看我們，有夠丟臉啊
You can be our legs!
機動力就靠你了
Use the suit's power to help you!
盡情發揮戰鬥服的力量吧
The broken bone hurts like hell, but...
雖然我骨折的地方超痛的…
Use all your knowledge to handle attacking!
就麻煩前輩活用知識，發動攻擊了
Right!
好
C-Can we just pass these guys?
這可以合格了吧？給他們搞笑組的名額
Take your job seriously!
你認真點！
Follow Kikoru and don't worry about me!
你不必顧慮我，快追上琪歌露
Hurry!
動作快
Got it!
知道了
Hang on tight!
你小心別摔下來
He's so damn fast!
好快啊
I'm gonna get there first!
第一名是我
Eat my dust.
我先走一步了
Get ready so you can support her once we catch up!
你準備一下，追上後立刻進行援護
Right! Leave it to me!
好，交給我
She's not even letting us help her, huh?
竟然連援護的機會都不給我們
Number 2016 has taken down the last Yoju in Area Delta,
2016號考生 已擊敗戴爾塔區最後一隻餘獸
and is now engaging the Honju!
現在與主獸交戰中
Last one.
最後一隻
T-The Honju has been destroyed.
主獸已被擊敗
The final stage of the exam is complete!
最終審查結束
Recovering drones.
開始回收無人機
Good work, everyone.
大家辛苦了
That girl is just too goddamn fast!
真假？那傢伙的動作也太迅速了吧
COMBINATION UNDONE
（合體解除）
While we bring back the drones,
我們要回收無人機
we also need to send medics for the injured.
同時救助傷者
Right, Vice-Captain Hoshina?
沒錯吧？保科副隊長
That was even faster than I thought.
這未免也太快了吧
It was so much work to set this all up, too.
我們花了很多心力準備耶
Kikoru Shinomiya's even more powerful than the rumors say.
四之宮琪歌露比傳聞還厲害啊
So she's enough to catch even your eye, huh?
厲害到引起你的興趣了嗎？
I'd imagined we'd see about thirty people drop out.
原本以為大概會淘汰三十個人
But nobody did.
結果卻是零
And with only minimal injuries.
傷者人數也在最低範圍內
And it's clearly all thanks to her.
很顯然都是因為她，才會有這個結果
That's what you'd expect to see from Director Shinomiya's daughter.
不愧是四之宮長官的女兒
She'll be a big shot in the Defense Force someday, that's for sure.
她無疑會成為防衛隊未來的梁柱
And a ray of hope for this country.
是這個國家的希望之光
I was perfect, wasn't I, Daddy?
我的表現很完美吧，爸爸？
Now, time to go back and laugh at Kafka Hibino a fourth time...
那我去看看日比野卡夫卡 第四次哭喪臉的模樣再回去…
Kikoru Shinomiya was every bit the monster everybody said she was, right?
四之宮琪歌露真的如傳聞所說的 是個怪物呢
Yeah.
對啊
She sure showed me up, just like she said she would.
結果我從頭到尾都只能哭喪著一張臉
But thanks to her, we made it to the end.
不過也多虧了她，才有辦法撐到最後
Now we just wait for the results.
剩下就等結果了
Yes...
是啊
What?
怎麼回事？
What's going on?
發生什麼事了？
Senpai, let's get out of here!
前輩，總之我們先去避難吧
I was barely able to protect my heart
靠著防護盾集中在一點
by focusing my entire shield on a single point.
才勉強保護了心臟
I can still fight!
我還能戰鬥
What the hell are you?
你這傢伙是什麼啊？
You're still moving?
還動得了啊？
It can talk?!
這傢伙會說話？
What's going on with that skin of yours?
你那個皮膚是什麼？
There, there. I'll let you handle this.
乖，接下來交給你囉
It's a Kaiju, but it's intelligent!
怪獸竟然擁有智慧？
What's going on?
這是怎麼回事？
Die!
你這傢伙！
Make sure you chew before you swallow.
記得要細嚼慢嚥喔
Something's wrong!
發生異常狀況
Abnormalities detected in 2016's vitals!
2016號的生命徵象出現異常
What's going on? What's happening out there?
怎麼回事？發生什麼事了？
I don't know!
不清楚
But we're picking up live signals from the Kaiju they already killed!
可是原本已經死亡的怪獸 現在又顯現反應了
What?
什麼？
Those Kaiju shouldn't be able to come back to life like that...
那些怪獸應該不具備這種特性
We have an estimated fortitude for the revived Honju!
復活後的主獸的推測怪獸規模出來了
It's 6.4!
是6.4
It's more powerful now?
強度還提高了？
You'd need a whole company to handle that.
這等級需要一個中隊才能處理
The only ones here capable of taking that thing down fast would be...
在場能單獨應付這種情形的人…
Activate remote shields for all examinees.
啟動所有考生的遠端防護盾
Yes, ma'am!
是！
Send back some of the drones and get me a camera feed.
把一部分無人機調回去拍攝現場狀況
Hoshina, we're heading out there.
保科，我們出動
...me or her.
…只有她跟我了
Roger.
瞭解
Emergency. Emergency.
發生緊急狀況
Examinees are to immediately evacuate to the nearest shelter.
請考生立即前往最近的避難所避難
I say again: examinees are to immediately
重複一次
Evacuate?
避難？
I can't evacuate...
我不能去避難
If somebody doesn't stop this thing,
要是沒人阻止這傢伙
lots of people will die!
會死很多人的
Stop the bleeding with Kaiju muscle fibers.
先用怪獸肌肉纖維讓傷口止血
I can still move. I can still fight!
我還動得了，我還能戰鬥
When I'm on the battlefield,
有我在的戰場
nobody dies!
我不允許有人犧牲
Be perfect, for the sake of this nation's future!
為了國家的未來，你得達到完美的境界
I need to be perfect!
我必須表現得很完美才行啊
I won't lose...
我不會輸的
Kikoru-chan, you're amazing!
琪歌露，你好厲害
Your name's at the very top!
你的名字在最上面耶
That means you're number one, right?
這代表你是第一名吧？
Yes! I was the top scorer!
沒錯，這叫榜首喔
Wow!
好厲害
Risa.
麗莎
Daddy!
爸爸
Congratulations on passing, Risa.
麗莎，恭喜你考上了
Don't pat me on the head like that, Daddy! It's embarrassing!
你別摸我的頭啦，很丟臉耶
I'll buy you that present, just like I promised.
我會按照約定，買禮物獎賞妳
Really? Hooray!
真的嗎？好棒
Bye, Kikoru-chan!
琪歌露，再見囉
Let's go get yakiniku to celebrate your hard work!
為了犒賞你的努力，我們去吃燒肉吧
I told you there was nothing to worry about.
就跟你說不用擔心了吧
I always had faith in you, son!
真不愧是我的兒子
Kikoru-sama.
琪歌露小姐
The master will be home today.
老爺今天會回家
I'm sure he'll be quite pleased.
他一定會很高興的
Yeah!
嗯
You got the top score?
榜首？
Of course you did. Who cares?
那是應該的吧
Rejoicing over a single success will only lead to failure next time.
對一次成功就過於執著容易讓人有機可乘
Get ready for your next goal immediately.
你要立刻朝下一個目標邁進
Kikoru.
琪歌露
Always be perfect, for the sake of this nation's future!
為了國家的未來，你得達到完美的境界
And for your late mother's sake, as well.
這也是為了告慰你母親在天之靈
Yes, sir...
好的
I won't lose!
我不會輸的
Never stop moving forward!
不能停下腳步！
I can still fight!
我還能戰鬥
Never let anyone be better than you!
不能讓別人迎頭趕上！
Even with one arm, as long as it can move, I can...
就算我只剩一隻手能動…
Be more powerful than anyone else on the battlefield!
你要成為無人能敵的存在！
I can still fight!
我還能戰鬥
No...
怎麼會…
Honju sighted!
發現主獸
Kikoru Shinomiya is nearby, and injured!
在附近的四之宮琪歌露受傷了
The Honju's severed offensive uniorgan has regenerated!
主獸被切除的攻擊性單器官再生了
It's condensing energy for an attack!
牠正在壓縮能量
Crap...
糟糕
Will we make it in time?
我們趕得及嗎？
I'm done for...
我已經…
I'm sorry, Daddy.
對不起，爸爸
I couldn't be perfect.
我沒辦法達到完美的境界
I'm sorry.
對不起
You did a great job, Kikoru!
琪歌露，你很努力了
What are you doing here?
你為什麼會在這裡？
Because you worked so hard, everybody was able to evacuate!
多虧你努力撐著，大家才能順利避難
Now leave the rest to me!
接下來就交給我吧
What the hell was that explosion?
剛才的爆炸是怎麼回事？
Damn it!
可惡
Get a move on!
別拖拖拉拉了
Get your asses into the shelter!
快點跑去避難所
A signal flare?
信號彈？
-You can run there, right? -Y-Yeah.
-你們跑得到那邊吧？ -嗯
He's guiding our evacuation, huh?
避難引導是嗎？
That's why he's the JGSDF's rising star!
真不愧是自衛隊的新星
Kafka-senpai...
卡夫卡前輩
Senpai, let's get out of here!
前輩，總之我們先去避難吧
The Honju came back to life!
主獸復活了
Don't head that way!
別往那裡跑
Shinomiya is fighting it right now!
四之宮正在那邊戰鬥
I told HQ!
我已經通知總部了
Everyone get out of here! That's an order!
大家快點逃跑，這是命令
Senpai, you heard that, right?
前輩，你聽到了吧？
He's already gone!
人跑哪了咧？
He's not going to transform, right?
他該不會變身了吧？
He's not, right?
應該不會吧？
If he turns into a Kaiju right now, he'll be killed for sure.
要是在這種狀況變成怪獸，一定會被殺死
No, he'll do it!
不對，他會變身
At times like this, he doesn't hesitate at all...
這種時候他絕不會猶豫的
What?
什麼？
What's going on?
這是怎麼回事？
You're a Kaiju?
你是怪獸？
Kikoru.
琪歌露
Please! Please!
求求你
Please don't tell the Defense Force about this!
拜託你別告訴防衛隊
Please!
求求你了
I'll tell you more in a bit.
詳情我之後再解釋
I only need a sec to kick this thing's ass.
我一秒就會解決牠
So just relax and get some rest.
你就放心休息吧
I'm detecting a mysterious ultra-powerful energy source near the Honju!
主獸附近偵測到神祕的超高能量反應
It might be a new Kaiju!
有可能是新的怪獸
Another one?
新的怪獸？
Do we have visual?
有影像嗎？
The explosion knocked out our comms network.
由於爆炸造成通訊障礙
We do not have visual.
影像難以辨識
Wait, is this number right?
這個數值是怎麼回事？
Fortitude 9.8?
怪獸規模9.8？
Impossible.
不可能吧
The blast must've scrambled the measurement system.
應該是爆炸的衝擊讓偵測器故障了吧
R-Right?
說得也是
Otherwise it'd be one of the most powerful Daikaiju in history!
如果不是故障 那就是留名青史的大怪獸了
Sorry. I'm running out of time here.
抱歉，我沒時間了
So I'm cleaning you up...
就讓我一拳…
with one punch!
把你解體
Let's see you come back to life after that!
有種你就復活看看啊
N-No! Just kidding!
我開玩笑的
Please don't come back to life!
拜託你還是別復活
Don't scare me like that!
何必嚇人呢？
Who is this guy?
這傢伙是怎麼回事？
A Yoju?
餘獸？
Looks like you'll be okay.
看樣子你還撐得下去
I'm glad you're safe!
幸好你沒事
But let me say one thing.
不過，有一句話我非說不可
You can't put yourself in danger like that!
你要好好愛惜自己啦
You too!
你也是啦！
Ichikawa! What are you doing here?
市川，你怎麼會在這裡？
You ran off while my back was turned,
你擅自就跑走
and sure enough, I find you here, transformed!
還不出我所料變身了
I was thinking maybe I could just transform a part of my body.
我本來以為可以變身一部分就好
But when I saw the Honju I was like, "No way!"
看到主獸後，才發現根本不可能
You need to be more careful!
總之你得更謹慎…
Shinomiya!
四之宮！
Ashiro and Hoshina have arrived at the scene.
亞白和保科抵達現場
What is this?
這是怎麼回事？
What would you have to do to cause this?
要怎麼打鬥才會變成這樣？
I've seen this before somewhere...
這副情景，好像似曾相識
Captain Ashiro, I can't find any of the examinees.
亞白隊長，我們沒發現考生
This is the operation room.
這裡是作戰室
An additional three examinees have arrived at Shelter 6.
第6避難所又收容了三名考生
It's Kikoru Shinomiya, Reno Ichikawa, and Kafka Hibino.
這三人是四之宮琪歌露 市川雷諾和日比野卡夫卡
They're safe, huh?
他們沒事啊
All examinees are now accounted for.
這樣一來，所有考生均已平安返回
Roger.
瞭解
I'll admit that Kikoru Shinomiya is strong,
雖然說四之宮琪歌露很強
but she can't have done this...
但也不至於能做到這地步
The Kaiju coming back to life, and then this blast zone...
先是怪獸復活，然後是這個爆炸現場
There's a lot we don't understand.
謎團實在太多了
Bring in an investigation unit and a disposal unit.
你們去叫調查組跟處理組過來
Hoshina and I will wipe out the remaining Yoju.
我跟保科去消滅剩下的餘獸
Roger.
瞭解
It's like what we saw three months ago...
這跟三個月前的那時候很像
Are they linked in some way?
這之間有什麼關聯嗎？
I'm glad to see you're not as badly hurt as I thought.
幸好你的傷勢沒有想像中嚴重
I'm back in the hospital...
我又住院了
Shinomiya's condition is looking good, too.
聽說四之宮也沒有生命危險
They're using the Defense Force's best tech to treat her, supposedly.
防衛隊正運用所有技術全力治療她
Why does she get better treatment? Let me in on that!
這是什麼差別待遇？我也要去那裡…
'Cause you only have a few fractures.
前輩你只是骨折而已啊
It was all over so fast.
真是一轉眼就結束了
It's been ages since I went up against people so incredible,
好久沒跟這麼厲害的對手競爭
and it reminded me...
這讓我想起一件事
Chasing your dreams means there's always someone out there
所謂的追逐夢想 就是在自己最在乎的事情上
who's beating you at the thing you care about most.
時時刻刻，不斷輸給別人
Senpai...
前輩
But it's also so exciting that you don't really care!
不過，卻也可以讓人熱血沸騰 覺得那些都無所謂了
It helped me remember that!
我想起了這件事
And I have you to thank for encouraging me.
這都要多虧你推了我一把
Thanks, Ichikawa.
謝謝你，市川
Captain Ashiro?
亞白隊長？
What are you doing here?
隊長你怎麼會來這裡？
I'm told you carried Shinomiya to the shelter.
我聽說是你們把四之宮帶回來的
Thank you for your help in rescuing her.
謝謝你們救了她一命
Goodbye.
打擾了
Mi...
米…
No, not yet.
不，時候未到
I'll talk to her after I become an officer!
我要等到成為隊員之後，再跟她搭話
Just watch me, Mina!
你等著看吧，米娜
Daddy, I couldn't be perfect...
爸爸，我沒達到完美的…
I...
我…
Daddy?
爸爸？
Oh, just stay there.
你躺著就好
Vice-Captain Hoshina.
保科副隊長
We dealt with all the Kaiju that revived.
復活的怪獸都被我們解決了
Fortunately, nobody was killed
幸好沒有人因此身亡
thanks to you taking down the Honju.
這都要多虧你解決了主獸
Is that not what happened?
我說錯了嗎？
I'm glad you're safe!
幸好你沒事
No, I defeated that Kaiju.
不，那隻怪獸是我打倒的沒錯
KOKUBUNJI, TOKYO
（東京都，國分寺市）
During a Defense Force screening exam,
防衛隊測驗會場
an unusual incident took place, with Kaiju suddenly coming back to life.
發生怪獸突然復活的事件
There were several injuries during the incident, but zero fatalities.
雖然造成數人受傷，但所幸無人死亡
Zero? Zero?
零？零？
No, no, no. No way there were zero.
不…那種狀況怎麼可能會是零？
Or is one of these "Captain" people that strong?
所謂的「隊長」真的那麼強嗎？
Kaiju No. 8 remains at large...
怪獸8號也仍下落不明…
No. 8? What?
什麼8號？
Um... this is how you answer a phone, right?
接電話是要按這裡吧？
Hey, where've you been?
你跑去哪裡了啊？
Breaktime's over, you know.
休息時間已經結束了
Uh...
啊…
Don't you "uh" me. Get back here.
啊什麼啊，快點回來
Right.
好的
I'll be right back.
我馬上回去
Sheesh. Humans are so particular about time.
真是的，人類對時間有夠囉唆
Sorry, sorry.
抱歉，真是不好意思
I had a bad case of diarrhea.
我有點拉肚子
You had us all worried, you know?
真是的，害我們很擔心
Tell someone where you're going before you hole up in the toilets, new kid.
上廁所至少先說一聲吧，你這個新來的
Sorry, Toku-san.
抱歉，德哥
Hey, I heard there was an accident at the exam site.
對了，聽說測驗會場發生事故
Seriously?
真假？
Oops.
唉呀…
Are Kafka and Ichikawa okay?
卡夫卡跟市川沒事吧？
How careless of me.
我可得小心點